Alicia Savelli

☑ aliciasavelli@gmail.com • ② aliciasavelli.github.io

I am an undergraduate student going into my final year of a physics degree at Brock University with previous Bachelor's degrees in mathematics and education. I am extremely passionate about astronomy, physics, mathematics, research, and teaching, and have significant experience and skills to support me in a career in science. I am interested in the fields of cosmology, galaxy formation and evolution, and relativity.

Education

2020 – 2022
2014 – 2019
2014 – 2019
2010 – 2014

Research Experience

Undergraduate Thesis

Exploring the Possibility of Faster-than-Light Travel in Our Universe *Supervisor: Prof. Barak Shoshany*

Brock University 2020 – 2021

- Using Mathematica and General Relativity to investigate the possibility of Faster-than-Light travel
- Extending the Alcubierre and Natario Warpdrive metrics to 5 spacetime dimensions
- Proposal, midterm, and final presentations to Faculty and interested public along with written thesis submission

Research Projects.

Analogues of the Milky Way in Cosmological Simulations

University of Toronto

Supervisors: Dr. Ted Mackereth & Dr. Josh Speagle

Summer 2021

 Used Python and data from the EAGLE suite of cosmological simulations to identify and analyze Milky Way Analogues (MWAs)

- Determined a "Milky Way-ness" parameter and studied its effect on various properties of the MWAs both at present-day and throughout their formation histories
- Midterm and final presentations, academic poster, and research summary delivered to Faculty and interested public

Galactic Archaeology using Milky Way Survey Data and Simulations Supervisors: Dr. Ted Mackereth & Dr. Josh Speagle

University of Toronto
Winter 2022

Publications

Exploring the Possibility of Faster-than-Light Travel in Our Universe

Alicia Savelli, Barak Shoshany

In prep.

Scholarships, Awards & Honours

Summer Undergraduate Research Program (SURP) Fellowship

Canadian Institute for Theoretical Astrophysics; Dunlap Institute for Astronomy & Astrophysics, \$9,595

2021

SURP Student Spotlight

Canadian Institute for Theoretical Astrophysics; Dunlap Institute for Astronomy & Astrophysics

2021

SURP Poster Contest – Runner Up

Canadian Institute for Theoretical Astrophysics; Dunlap Institute for Astronomy & Astrophysics

2021

Dean's Honour List

Brock University

2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2021

- Awarded to students with an 80% average or greater each academic year
- Received every year of B.Sc. (Math) & B.Sc. (Physics) degrees
- Additional distinction of top 15% of the faculty

Brock Scholars Award

Brock University, \$8,000

2014, 2015, 2016, 2017

- Entrance scholarship for incoming averages of 90% or greater
- \$2,000/year for a maximum of 4 years, renewed if average is maintained at 80% or greater

Ontario Scholar

Halton Catholic District School Board

2014

- Distinction for graduating students with an average of 79.5% or greater in top six grade 12 courses

Top Hat Marching Orchestra Scholarship

Top Hat Marching Orchestra, \$1,000

2014

French Second Language Award

Halton Catholic District School Board, \$50

2014

- Awarded to graduating student with the highest mark in a grade 12 French course

Conference Talks

SDSS-V 2021 Collaboration Meeting

Johns Hopkins University/Online

Analogues of the Milky Way in Cosmological Simulations

August 2021

Conference Posters

SDSS-V 2021 Collaboration Meeting

Wembley High Technology College

Johns Hopkins University/Online

Analogues of the Milky Way in Cosmological Simulations

August 2021

Teaching Experience

Secondary Teacher

London, UK

Secondary Maths Teacher

September 2019 – July 2020

- Taught five maths classes from the GCSE Foundation and Higher curricula to Key Stage 3 and Key stage 4 learners at various levels of academic achievement
- Developed and delivered engaging and differentiated lessons, managed classroom behaviour, regularly assigned and marked homework
 - Year 9 form tutor
- Volunteered to participate in and organize extra curricular activities such as a tutoring club, a puzzles club, a maths news letter, and UKMT national maths challenges

St. John Henry Newman Catholic Secondary School (HWCDSB)

Hamilton, ON

April – May 2019

- B.Ed. Practicum

Physics Student Teacher

- Taught one SPH3U grade 11 universy level physics class and two SPH4U grade 12 university level physics classes
- Entirely responsible for creating notes and lessons that delivered the curriculum, and developing and marking tests, quizzes, assignments, and lab experiments/reports
- Volunteered with the school's concert band and lunchtime and after-school tutoring/homework clubs

Cathedral High School (HWCDSB)

Hamilton, ON

Math Student Teacher

November – December 2018

- B.Ed. Practicum
- Taught one MPM1D grade 9 academic level math class and one MCR3U grade 11 university level math class
- Entirely responsible for creating notes and lessons that delivered the curriculum, and developing and marking tests, quizzes, and assignments
 - Volunteered with the after-school homework club

Prince of Wales South Public School (NDSB)

Primary Teacher

Thorold, ON

Student Teacher

October 2015 - March 2016

- B.Ed. Practicum
- Delivered Levelled Literacy Intevervention (LLI) program
- Helped students of all ages advance their reading levels in small groups of three to four students

Professional Primary, Secondary, & Post-Secondary Tutor.....

Oxford Learning

Burlington & Hamilton, ON

Teacher

May 2017 – Present

- Tutor in groups of one to three high school students, and occasionally students at the college or primary levels
 - Specialize in intermediate and senior level math, calculus, data management, and physics, but

also tutor students in chemistry, general science, English, French, and more

Private Tutor

Independent Private Tutor

2014 - Present

– One-on-one private tutoring in all levels and categories of secondary math and science and first-year math and physics

Other

Education Quality and Accountability Office

Etobicoke, ON

July 2019

2015-2016

Score

- Scored academic- and applied-level grade 9 math EQAO tests

Brock University Mathematics Department

St. Catharines, ON

Exam Proctor

- Proctored first-year math midterms and final exams

Other Relevant Work Experience

McDonalds Canada Burlington, ON

Team Leader, Crew

2013 – 2019

- Responsibilities included area and shift management, customer service, order taking & filling, and birthday parties
- Transferable skills to research and education include strong leadership & team management, collaboration, time management, stress management, organization, and communication

ArcelorMittal Dofasco Hamilton, ON

Summer 2018

Data Analyst Summer 2018

- Developed and enhanced queries and data reports to improve company efficiency, wrote macros to supplement reports
 - Enhanced technical skills with Visual Basic, SQL, MS Excel, and MS Access

Workshops, Training, & Professional Development

Introduction to Python
Student
University of Toronto
May 2021

- 2-week intensive introductory course to coding and data analysis with Python
- Covered topics such as advanced plotting, statistical analysis, and machine learning

SURP Astro 101 Lecture Series

University of Toronto

Summer Research Student

Summer 2021

- Summer series of weekly introductory astronomy lectures
- Topics covered included planets & explanets, galaxy formation & evolution, instrumentation, statistics, cosmology, and black holes

SURP Professional Development Series

University of Toronto

Summer Research Student

Summer 2021

- Summer series of weekly professional development workshops and seminars
- Topics covered included careers in astronomy, grad school applications and experiences, and presenting research

Shutdown STEM
Attendee

University of Toronto

July 2021

- Day-long workshop within the Astronomy & Astrophysics department pertaining to action

against racism with a special focus on Indigenous peoples

- Workshop included presentations, discussions, and activities such as researching and letterwriting

SAFETALK Mental Health Training

Brock University

March 2018

- Training in speaking to young people about their mental health and the best ways to be available and offer support
 - Awarded certificate

Relevant Coursework

- o Astronomy: Introduction to Astronomy, Planetary Science
- Physics: Classical Mechanics, Electromagnetism, Quantum Mechanics, Statstical Mechanics & Thermal Physics, Optics, Special & General Relativity, Experimental Physics
- Mathematics: Calculus, Vector Calculus, Differential Equations, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Mathematical Physics, Differential Geometry
- **Computer Programming:** Mathematics Integrated with Computers and Applications I/II/III, Introduction to Scientific Computing
- o Education: Mathematics, Physics, Diversity, Special Education

Technical & Personal Skills

- o Programming Languages: Python, Visual Basic, SQL, Physica, Extrema
- o **Software:** Maple, Mathematica, LATEX, Git
- o Operating Systems: Windows, Linux
- o Professional Skills: Presenting, writing, teaching
- **Personal Skills:** Enthusiasm, organization, communication, time management, leadership, collaboration, perseverance, diligence

Professional Memberships

Ontario College of Teachers (OCT)

Member ID: 698209

2019 – Present

Extracurricular Activities

Burlington Concert Band

Burlington, ON 2018-2019

Brock University Winds Ensemble

St. Catharines, ON

 2^{nd} Clarinet

1st Clarinet

2014-2018

Brock Intramural Sports

Brock University

Soccer, Baseball, Volleyball

2016-2018

Media Appearances

SURP Project Showcase <u>Poster</u> , Research Summary	2021
SURP Student Spotlight Student of the Week interview	2021
A university mathematics department's adoption of constructionist math courses MICA Project interview	2017